Elijah Vitoesi

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

vitoesitemitope@gmail.com | GitHub | LinkedIn | Twitter | Portfolio | AngelList

SUMMARY

I'm a passionate Full-stack web developer with a background in developing efficient software applications in a global market. 2+ years of experience, including mentoring 10+ junior developers to achieve concrete goals on a strict deadline. I have expertise in a variety of coding languages, tools, and techniques, and I can quickly learn and adapt to new ones. Additionally, I'm enthusiastic about collaborating with a team. Strong skills include React, Database management, PostgreSQL, and Ruby.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS

Remote

Full Stack Web Developer

August 2022 - Present

<u>Math magicians</u> —This project was created for users to perform basic calculations and read a random statement about arithmetic.

Built with: HTML5, CSS5 and React

<u>VECS-School</u> — The system is designed to facilitate the booking of courses by allowing users to specify their city and preferred dates. It provides a set of robust and well-documented endpoints that enable seamless communication between the frontend applications & the backend

Built with: React, Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL and Bootstrap

<u>Bookstore</u> — This website was created for users to add, display, and remove a selected displayed book. Built with React and use Redux as state manager.

Built with: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript and React-Redux

MICROVERSE Remote

Mentor (Volunteer) April 2023 – Present

- Mentored 10 junior web developers weekly, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organisation to improve code quality and overall performance by 92 per cent.
- Provided advice and tips on maintaining motivation to over 125 students to maintain longevity in the program.

DANNYOKEC AGENCY

Abuja, Nigeria

Junior Frontend Developer

November 2022 - February 2023

- Deliver 24+ projects of all sizes, creating solutions for over 45 consumer services monthly.
- Evaluated 10+ end-to-end designs for performance complexity, scalability, quality, and security weekly.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE

November, 2022 - Present

Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full-Time

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair programming using GitHub, industry-standard git-flow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.

THE FEDERAL UNIVERSITY OF AGRICULTURE, ABEOKUTA.

M.Sc, Agricultural Economics

August 2020 - October 2022

Awards and honours: Stood up among the top 50 student union governments in the country